Now, we finally have all the tools for describing the perceptron algorithm.
パーセプトロンアルゴリズムを記述するツールがすべて揃いました
We start with the random equation,
まずランダム式
which will determine some line,
これは何らかの直線と
and two regions, the positive and the negative region.
2つの領域 つまり 正と負の領域を決めます
Now, we'll move this line around to get a better and better fit.
今度はこの直接を動かして 徐々に改善していきます
So, we ask all the points how they're doing.
そして すべてのポイントに調子を尋ねます
The four correctly classified points say, "I'm good."
正しく分類されている4つのポイントは「私は大丈夫」と答えます
And the two incorrectly classified points say, "Come closer."
誤って分類されている2つのポイントは「もう少し近づいて」と答えます
So, let's listen to the point in the right,
では 右のポイントに聞いてみて
and apply the trick to make the line closer to this point.
トリックを適用し 直線をこのポイントに近づけましょう
So, here it is. Now, this point is good.
され こうなりました  このポイントは大丈夫になりました
Now, let's listen to the point in the left.
今度は左のポイントに聞いてみましょう
The points says, "Come closer."
このポイントは「もう少し近づいて」と言います
We apply the trick,
トリックを適用し
and now the line goes closer to it,
直線が近づき
and it actually goes over it classifying correctly.
ついにポイントを超えて 正しく分類されました
Now, every point is correctly classified and happy.
これで すべてのポイントが正しく分類され ハッピーになりました
So, let's actually write the pseudocode for this perceptron algorithm.
では このパーセプトロンアルゴリズムの疑似コードを実際に書いてみましょう
We start with random weights,
まずランダム重み
w1 up to wn and b.
w1からwnまでとbで始めます
This gives us the question wx plus b,
これでwx+bという式ができ
the line, and the positive and negative areas.
直線と正と負の領域ができます
Now, for every misclassified point with coordinates x1 up to xn,
今度は誤って分類され 座標x1からxnまでのすべてのポイントについて
we do the following.
次のようにします
If the prediction was zero,
予測がゼロの場合
which means the point is a positive point in the negative area,
ポイントは負の領域にある正のポイントであることを意味するので
then we'll update the weights as follows: for i equals 1 to n,
重みを次のように更新しますi=1からnについて
we change wi, to wi plus alpha times xi,
wiをwi+αかけるxiに変更します
where alpha is the learning rate.
αは学習率です
In this case, we're using 0.1.
この例では 0.1を使用します
Sometimes, we use 0.01 etc.
ときには0.01などを使用します
It depends. Then we also change the bi as unit to b plus alpha.
場合によります次にバイアスユニットもb+αに変更します
That moves the line closer to the misclassified point.
これで直線は誤って分類されているポイントに近づきます
Now, if the prediction was one,
予測が1の場合
which means a point is a negative point in the positive area,
ポイントは正の領域にある負のポイントであることを意味するので
then we'll update the weights in a similar way,
重みを同様に更新しますが
except we subtract instead of adding.
足す代わりに引きます
This means for i equals 1, change wi,
つまり i=1について
to wi minus alpha xi,
wiをwi-α xiに変更し
and change the bi as unit b to b minus alpha.
バイアスユニットbをb-αに変更します
And now, the line moves closer to our misclassified point.
これで直線は誤って分類されているポイントに近づきます
And now, we just repeat this step until we get no errors,
このステップをエラーがなくなるか
or until we have a number of error that is small.
エラーの数が小さくなるまで続けます
Or simply we can just say,
または単に
do the step a thousand times and stop.
ステップを1000回繰り返してから中止すると言うこともできます
We'll see what are our options later in the class.
オプションについては クラスで後述します